Ashley Lester | Analyst

Computing graduate and data analyst passionate about information visualisation, databases and system development. Wide experience of reporting and modelling packages including BOXI and Oracle. I use insightful analysis to support strategic decision-making, and I develop systems and processes so that customers can optimise and manage their business areas.

Education

Academic Qualifications

Bachelor of Science (Hons) Computing
Open University, Upper-Second Class Honours

Nottingham *2010–2014*

3 A Levels & 1 AS Level

Nottingham

Lakeview College, Maths (C), Spanish (B), Geography (B), AS Music (B)

2004–2006

11 GCSEs

Nottingham

Chilwell Comprehensive School, Incl. Maths (A), Science (AA), English (A*), Geography (A*)

1999–2004

Academic & Personal Projects.....

o Undergraduate Dissertation: 'A Distributed Software System for Housing Surveys Using Mobile Devices'

My qualification focussed on software aspects of system development: requirements analysis, design, programming and validation. I also took modules in AI, interaction design and relational database theory. This dissertation followed a full development lifecycle of a software project and consisted of a website, database and Android application.

o After Graduation: Personal website and blog, data visualisation, and other projects

I am working on several projects in my spare time. I am creating web-based interactive data visualisations with JavaScript (see an example here: https://intense-coast-2111.herokuapp.com/). I am also implementing a Ruby library for artificial intelligence algorithms, and I keep a personal website which contains project information and a blog.

Employment

Metropolitan Housing Partnership

Nottingham

Data Intelligence Analyst

April 2012-Present

Metropolitan is one of the biggest private housing associations in the UK, with 40,000 tenants. Our analytics team cover all areas from rents to regulatory reports to customer demographics. The company has completed a major data migration project, and our team have built its reporting services from scratch. I give front-line customers the capability to view real-time status updates, creating dashboards for the repairs service and empty homes service. The most basic and important function of our team is to provide stakeholders with a trusted set of consistent MI reports. I enjoy focusing on deployment, which makes sure our solutions are used by our customers and improved over time. Recently, I am also exploring interfaces with Experian, and customer modelling techniques, driving initiatives from reward programs to investigating sub-letting.

RBS Nottingham
Business Executive 2011–2012

I managed my own portfolio of customers on debt management plans, offering advice on good financial practice, and taking customers through income & expenditure assessments. After 6 months I moved to complaints, writing responses by letter to customers in relation to bank charges and indebtedness. The level of formal written English had to be very high, and the decisions I made day to day had a huge impact on the financial status of my customers.

Halifax Nottingham

Mortgage Servicing Consultant

2010-2011

I worked in a fast-paced call centre, processing requests for borrowing and product changes, and cross-selling financial products.

Technical and Personal

- o **Development:** Good amount of experience writing SQL queries. Working knowledge of Java, Ruby, HTML5 and web technologies. Knowledge of software development methodologies and concepts such as APIs, web services, design patterns, object-orientation and requirements analysis techniques: UML, business activity diagrams, use cases and writing specifications. Knowledge of the LATEX typesetting language.
- o **Software:** I have worked or am working with the following tools: Oracle Discoverer, Crystal Reports, Business Objects (WEBI) and Microsoft Dynamics. Familiar with Oracle, Sybase and PostgreSQL. Advanced Excel and Access user.
- o **Business:** Good relationships with executive directors, directors and heads of service. I enjoy teaching colleagues to use WEBI and Excel, and I enjoy working with stakeholders throughout projects, including after deployment.